another one because guess what I've got
another adjustable dumbbell review for
you guys adjustable dumbbells are an
absolute game changer for anyone who's
tied on space and they're also a much
cheaper alternative than purchasing a
full set of traditional dumbbells I've
been using the PowerBlock Pro 50s a lot
lately and I'm excited to break them
down for y'all
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake and I've
got the power block Pro 50s in the
garage for review now in this video I'm
going to tell you everything you need to
know about these adjustable dumbbells
from the price some of the features some
of the pros some of the cons but most
importantly who should or maybe should
not buy these now before I get going
with all of that good stuff I gotta let
you know we've reviewed a lot I'm
talking a lot of adjustable dumbbells on
barbin.com so if you want to browse our
best list just go ahead and search bar
Bend best adjustable dumbbells our list
is going to pull up for you and you can
find out for yourself which ones that we
like the best
okay so there's a lot to like about
these dumbbells but first of all you
know once again this is a great space
saving solution as you can see you know
they're not very big they kind of
resemble a shoebox in my opinion now
they're definitely taller than a shoebox
but the length and the width are about
you know what you will find you know
with a new pair of shoes now these are
also going to replace 20 individual
dumbbells which is a really nice thing
and it's also really easy to adjust the
weight so all you have to do is pull out
on this selector pin right here and
choose exactly where you want it to go
so these side rails are color coded and
it's going to be in direct correlation
with this weight chart that's right here
on the actual dumbbell so that way you
know exactly how much weight that you're
selecting this selector pin is also
magnetized so you know you really don't
have to worry about it coming undone as
you're working out and everything
falling on you it's not going to happen
the overall design right here is going
to make it a really quick process in
terms of removing the dumbbell well and
placing it back in the cradle and
there's actually not even a cradle
because this is the whole dumbbell right
here itself there's 50 pounds of weight
for you to work with so that's a pretty
good number for a lot of people the
handle is rubber but it's still pretty
grippy and it has a diameter of one and
a half inches so it's Gonna Fill your
palm really nicely and these are also
really durable because these are steel
weight plates that are coated in
urethane so durability really should not
be an issue for you whatsoever
[Music]
foreign
there's still a few things that some of
you may not be too crazy about and let's
talk about the max weight first so these
max out at 50 pounds as I just mentioned
and yeah that might be plenty for a lot
of people but there's also a lot of
people that need a lot more weight than
that now in terms of adjustable
dumbbells there's a couple out there
that you can purchase but they're going
to be more expensive than these are and
these are pretty expensive to say the
least before taxes and everything you
know you're going to be spending around
500 on these adjustable dumbbells and
they're also pretty bulky I mean as I
mentioned you know this is the actual
dumbbell right here so as you're you
know you have 50 pounds you're going to
do some shoulder presses maybe you know
bicep curl if you can curl that much
weight you know you're going to do some
dumbbell bench press whatever it may be
you know overall size right here might
just be a little bit clunky it might
make your movements a little bit
different and I don't personally have a
problem with with the handle here but
you know it is made out of rubber you
know doesn't have any type of knurling
and you know some people may not be
crazy about that so if I just describe
to you you might want to check out some
other options out there
[Music]
okay so let's expand on the money now
the power block Pro 50s are available
for right around 500 bucks but once you
tackle on your shipping and your taxes
you're gonna be spending over six
hundred dollars okay so yeah 600 that's
a lot of money but my opinion they're
really good quality if that makes things
you know a little bit easier on you
however you can definitely go down a
cheaper route if you want to do so so
you know there's some adjustable
dumbbells that are available for about
500 bucks with everything included but
you're most likely going to be dealing
with a lot of plastic which there's some
plastic here for sure but not as much as
those cheaper options on the flip side
there's some adjustable dumbbells that
are about nine hundred dollars so yes
these are expensive but it's not like
they're the most expensive adjustable
dumbbells on the market
okay so let's talk about the build now
and some of the features you're going to
experience with the power block Pro 50s
okay so once again these weight plates
are made from steel and they're coated
in urethane so in terms of durability
you know that's a really nice touch yes
the handle is made from rubber and
doesn't have any knurling on it but I
still think it's pretty grippy it feels
pretty good in my hands and that one and
a half inch diameter you know fills your
palm really nicely and it's also
technically ergonomically shaped now not
you know as much so as some other
dumbbells I've reviewed for y'all but
you know that shape is definitely still
there you can definitely feel it
you know in terms of actual size they're
not that big they're kind of tall but as
they're sitting on the ground you know
they're not going to take up that much
space they're a little over a foot long
about 13 inches and they're right around
seven inches wide might be a little
bulky as you're doing some workouts but
you know it's about the same size as a
shoe box maybe a little bit bigger so
it's not going to dominate too much
space in your home it's really easy to
adjust the weight you know once again
all you have to deal with is this
selector pin you know just simply pull
out select where you want it to go and
it's magnetized so it's not like it's
going to fall out on you also another
really nice touch right here is the
weight reference chart so you know all
these color-coded rails you know
correspond with this reference chart and
it makes it super easy for you to adjust
that weight just simply check it out see
what you want to work out with and
you're good to go and this is listed in
both kilograms and pounds which is you
know just a nice touch
[Applause]
all right so let's go ahead and do a
quick walk around with the power block
Pro 50s I want to talk about this color
coding side railing right here it's
really nice you know it's a really nice
touch every single one of these railings
you know corresponds with the reference
chart right here that way you know
exactly how much weight you're using and
you don't really have to think about it
now it's a really simple process in
terms of actually changing the weight
simply pull out on this selector pin and
you know wherever you want it to go so
let's say you want 20 pounds right well
on the white put that right there and
slide it in and you're going to have
exactly 20 pounds and the selector pin
is magnetized so once again you know
it's not going to fall out on you it's a
really nice touch now something that's
also really cool right here
actually have some two and a half pound
increments that you can work with and
that's because you have these two
ballast weights in the actual underneath
the handle I guess you could say and you
can take these out whenever you want to
so you do have this little release pin
right here all you have to do is simply
pull out on it and twist it a little bit
it's going to allow you to take both of
these out if you want to so
when you have them out this thing is
going to weigh five pounds right here
and it tells you right here on this
reference chart as well so when it's
empty there's five pounds one of them in
seven and a half both of them in this is
gonna weigh 10 pounds so that way you
know you definitely can work in some two
and a half pound increments if you need
to and to put them back you know it's
just reverse process just slide them in
there
and then position this back where it was
you know lock it and you're good to go
They're not going to fall out on you
you can set them right back and actually
you know what before I put them back I
want to talk about this handle yeah this
is made from rubber you know not
everybody's going to be crazy about that
but it's not that bad you know your
hand's going to fit nice and firm in
there it's got that one and a half inch
diameter and overall it just gives me a
pretty solid grip as I'm working out
which is you know obviously a good thing
and you know because of this design you
know this is going to slide in and out
super easily but you know bad thing
about the design is that they're pretty
bulky right I mean this isn't sitting in
a cradle this is the actual dumbbell so
whenever you have this set to 50 pounds
you know it can be a little bit weird as
you're going to do some shoulder presses
or you know whatever because they just
take up a good amount of space but I do
like how these steel weight plates are
coated in urethane it's just going to
protect you know the actual Integrity of
the plates and keep them around for a
long time
foreign
block Pro 50 adjustable dumbbells well
anyone who's super tight on Space you
know you want to make the most of that
available space obviously this is a
really good option for you to consider
because of the reference chart and the
color-coded side rails you know and that
selector pin it's a really simple
process in terms of adjusting the weight
so if that's something you know it's
going to be you know make a break for
you that's something that these really
have going on for them and if you don't
need more than 50 pounds of weight I
mean this is a really good option as
well because of the durability they're
likely going to last you a lifetime
[Music]
now when it comes to those who might not
want to purchase these dumbbells it
really just boils down to three
different things so let's talk about the
weight first you know once again these
max out at 50 pounds that definitely
might not be enough weight for everybody
out there so if you need more weight
than that you know you definitely want
to keep looking power block does make a
90 pound set that you might be
interested in
let's talk about the money now yeah
these are pretty expensive they're right
around 600 bucks if you want to save a
little bit of money there's some cheaper
adjustable dumbbells out there but
remember they might not be as durable as
these are and then lastly you know it's
just the shape you know
if you're using 50 pounds you know this
is the full thing right here so it's
going to be kind of bulky you know it
might you know impact your movements a
little bit and if that's something that
you're worried about then I definitely
suggest checking out some other options
well that's all I have for you guys
today on the power block Pro 50
adjustable dumbbells power blocks are
pretty classic in my opinion you know
this design right here tends to be what
I think about when people you know bring
up adjustable dumbbells they're really
easy to adjust the weight they're really
easy to move around overall you know
they're really good quality and I think
they're going to last you a lifetime
just remember they are a little bit
bulky and they're also pretty pricey too
but if you don't need more than 50
pounds of weight I think this is a great
option that you should consider thanks
for watching everybody I hope this video
was really helpful and that I was able
to tell you everything you need to know
about these adjustable dumbbells as
always stay on the lookout for my next
video but for now you should definitely
head over to barbin.com and read more
about these bad boys right here just
search bar Bend power block adjustable
dumbbell review and you'll find all the
details everything I discussed here
today is going to be in that article
I'll see y'all next time
[Music]